[ Crowd Sounds ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Good morning, everyone.
&gt;&gt; 大家早上好
And welcome to session 237 this
欢迎大家在周五的凌晨
early Friday morning.
来到 237 分会场
My name is Fredrik Olsson and
我叫 Fredrik Olsson
I'm an engineer on the MapKit
我是 MapKit 团队的一名工程师
And today I'm here to talk about
今天我在这里
what's new in MapKit.
想跟大家聊聊 Mapkit 的新鲜事
The generic map, the standard
很久之前
map that has been with us for a
我们就有了
couple of iterations all the
一般的 标准的地图
time, is a good map.
也的确是不错的地图
It has a road network for easy
其道路网络
navigation.
利于导航
You have your points of interest
你可根据自己的意愿
for reference.
来参考地图
But sometimes your application
但有时地图应用程序
has a little bit more specific
上面的信息
kind of data that you want to
有些过于细致
stand out.
以至于你想突出显示一些信息
Like we had in AppleMaps when we
就比如 Apple 地图
added the transit mode when we
我们打开公交模式的时候
want the transit line to stand
我们希望自己的线路可以突出显示
up and the map to take a little
地图的其他信息
bit of a step back, mute down
可以淡去
and let the data pop so the user
凸显出的信息
can see what is important at the
能让用户第一时间
moment.
看到最重要的东西
In new iOS 11, we give you muted
新的 iOS 11 系统中
standard map type but do the
提供了这种可淡去的标准地图
same for your applications so
对应用程序也做出了相同的改变
that your data can stand out on
所以你的信息可以
your map and your applications.
在你的地图 你的应用程序中凸显出来
The map is not only the map.
这个地图不仅仅是地图
There are also a couple of
我们还免费提供了
system controls that we provide
一些系统控制
for free on top of the map.
就在地图上面
You have up in the left corner
你可以在左上角这里
here you can see the scale view.
看到比例尺
You have the complex view up in
右上角
the right corner.
是指南针
And down in the bottom right you
右下角
have a friend that has been
是一直可在
available as API for your use,
应用程序界面使用的
the user tracking bar bottom
用户底部追踪栏项目
Now, it is a bar bottom item
这是个底部栏
which means that you can only
意味着
use it within the context of a
你只能在
bar, such as navigation bars or
栏中使用
tool bars.
比如导航栏和工具栏
And if you want to display it
如果
anywhere else, you have to
你想把它挪到别的地方
unfortunately roll your own.
那么你只能自己来
And in iOS 11 we fixed that and
在 iOS 11 中 我们改进了这个问题
we give you a proper user
我们提供了合适的
tracking button that is the
用户追踪按钮
UIView subclass so that you can
是个视图子类
use it wherever and whenever it,
这样的话
well is good for the context of
只要利于应用程序的使用
your application.
你就可以随时随地使用它
When we give you the user
当我们提供了用户追踪按钮之后
tracking button, we thought why
我们就在想
not give you more?
为什么不多提供一些呢
So, yes we will now also give
所以
you the compass button.
我们把指南针按钮也放了上来
The compass button is by
指南针按钮放在
standard app in the upper right
标准应用程序的
corner.
右上角
By having it as a UIView button
这是一个用户界面视图按钮
you can position it wherever you
你可以
want.
把它放在任何你想放的位置
You can even put it in one of
甚至
the navigation bars if you want
如果你想把它放在导航按钮上面
to.
都是可以的
The compass button has one more
指南针按钮
property than the user tracking
要比用户追踪按钮
button do.
多一个功能
It's the compass visibility.
那就是指南针可视性
It's on purpose that the compass
指南针可视性
visibility is not just
不是单单
repurposing the hidden property
把隐藏属性展示出来
or some equal simple bool yes
也不是简单的布尔选择
show it or don't show it.
要不要显示
We already could show the
我们
compass on the map view by using
早就在地图视图里
the shows compass on the map
加入了
view itself.
指南针
Which is a Boolean yes no.
这就是是与否的布尔选择
But it's a bit limited and
所以它很有局限性
doesn't encompass all the
也没有
features that we want to expose.
所有我们想要的功能
So, feature visibility is a new
所以功能可视性
enum.
是新的尝试
It has three states.
有如下三种状态
The adaptive mode which is the
默认是适应模式
default, hidden and visible.
还有隐藏和可视模式
And if you look at them, hidden
隐藏模式
is obvious.
很明显
It does what it says.
行如其名
Visible also does what it says,
可视模式也是这样
so no reason to talk much more
所以
about it.
就不过多讨论了
But the adaptive default mode do
但是
require a little bit of
我需要解释一下
explanation.
默认适应模式
What the adaptive mode do is
适应模式下
that if the user has rotated the
若用户
map a little bit away from pure
将方向旋转一点点偏离正北
north, we display it.
指南针会指示方向
And if the user rotates back to
若用户旋转回正北
pure north, we fade it away.
指南针符号消失
And being a button, if you tap
若用户轻点指南针按钮
on it we will rotate back to
地图会
pure north and fade it away as
旋回正北
well.
指南针符号就会消失
It is tapable in all the
在所有状态下
different visibility states, so
该按钮都是可按的
you can always tap it.
所以你可以永远轻点它
It will always be a button.
它一直都是一个按钮
But it's a nice catch.
但是你得点到它
And if the user rotates away
若用户将地图
from pure north past the little
从正北旋过一定角度
threshold, we fade it in again.
按钮也会消失
And that is the compass button.
以上是指南针按钮介绍
The last sibling, the scale
最后一个功能
view.
比例尺
Also have the visibility
也有可视功能
property which is the same three
同样
states in enumeration.
也有三个状态
Hidden, self-explanatory.
隐藏模式不需解释
Visible, also self-explanatory.
可视模式同样不需解释
And adaptive is a new behavior
适应模式是新模式
where when your user is zooming
用户缩放地图时
in and out, then we display the
比例尺图标
scale view.
就会出现
Otherwise, we hide it.
其他时候我们会隐藏它
The scale view has also been
之前的地图里
available on map view previously
也有比例尺图标
with the show scale property on
以显示
map view.
地图的比例尺
The default behavior for show
比例尺
scale and show compass has
和指南针
unfortunately been a little bit
的默认模式
different.
有些许不同
So, where the default for
指南针的默认模式
showing the compass has been the
是适应模式
adaptive mode where we hide it,
指南针按钮会隐藏
the default for scale has been
比例尺默认模式
to always show it.
是一直显示图标
And now with the scale view
一直显示比例尺图标
being exposed to you, you have
用户可选择
all three options available to
三种模式
use as it fits in your
以更好地
applications.
适应应用程序
There is one more property on
比例尺
the scale view.
还有一个功能
The legend alignment.
图标对齐
to the also new and improved
与新的改进的
localization support for map
地图视图定位支持
view.
有关
Previously, the compass has
之前
always been in the upper right.
指南针一直在右上角
The scale has always been in the
比例尺
upper left.
一直在左上角
These are the defaults you get.
这是默认的
But new in iOS 11, if you
但 iOS 11 系统里面
recompile against iOS 11 SDK, we
若再编译 iOS 11 系统的软件开发工具包
will instead fix the compass
我们会将
against the trailing edge and
指南针放到尾源
the scale view against the
比例尺放到前源
leading edge to get that natural
以便为从右到左的用户
look and feel for our
提供
right-to-left users.
自然的视图
This, however, has one little
但图标对齐
complication that leads us into
和我们开发该功能的原因
legend alignment property and
也给我们
why we need it.
带来了困难
The default is leading, which
默认是前源
means that we will fit the
意味着
serial point of the legend to
我们要让串行点
the edge, the leading edge.
放在前源
And the upper bound of the
图标的上半部分
legend is flexible and will move
很灵活
as the users zoom in and out.
在用户缩放时也会移动
And the leading edge for in this
此例中的前源
example British English would be
在英国
the left-hand side.
就是左手边
And for Arabic in this example
对阿拉伯人
is always the right-hand side.
这是右手边
If you instead want to align
如果你想
your scale view to the opposite
把比例尺图标
side of the screen, you need to
放到屏幕另一边
set the legend alignment
你需要设置
property to trailing and we will
图标对齐功能
flip the zero point that is
我们将重置固定的零点
fixed and to dynamically adapt
以使其
to the localization that is
灵活适应
currently being used.
当前定位
This makes a little bit more
若我们将其视为
sense if we look at it as the
用户与地图之间
user actually interacts with the
实际上的互动
map.
那就比较有意义了
The zero point, the zero points
所有零点
are fixed but as the user starts
当用户还没开始时都是固定的
zooming and this animates, the
但用户缩放地图 零点就不固定了
upper edge is moving.
上边缘在移动
And if that upper edge is the
若上边缘靠屏幕较近
closer edge to the screen, it
零点在中间
looks kind of silly as the zero
一动不动
point in the middle of the
而
screen is fixed but the other
另一个却在移动
one is moving.
这看起来有点蠢
So, you need to change it if you
所以
align the scale view to another
如果你将比例尺在另一页上对齐
page.
就需要改变
In using this simple APIs, the
使用这简单的应用程序界面时
muted standard map and exposed
可淡去的标准地图
map controls, we can take this
及其控制可让我们
fictional bike sharing
使用
application that we look at
现在神奇的
today.
共享单车软件
It is an application that allows
这是在
us to share unicycles and
旧金山地区
tricycles in the San Francisco
共享单轮脚踏车和三轮车的
area.
软件
We can take this application
我们
that is a little bit dated and
可使这一有点过时的应用程序
making it slightly more modern.
稍微现代一点
Now, let's look at that one more
现在
time.
我们再来看一遍
It was a little bit small of a
可能
difference maybe.
仅有一点点不同
We can take the slightly dated
我们
application and bring it to the
把这个有点过时的应用程序
future.
带向未来
As we see here, the big
如图所示
difference might not necessarily
地图模式
have been the map mode and the
和控制系统
controls.
没有太大的变化
The important part on your maps
您的应用程序里地图
in your application is your
的重要部分是
data, your annotations,
数据 注解
overlays, etc. And this is what
重复占位段等等
we are going to focus on next.
这也是我们接下来关注的方面
The standard way to display our
我们显示注解的
annotations has been the pin
标准方式是
annotation view since I was two
两天前开始的
days.
大头针注解
The pin annotation view comes in
大头针注解视图
two different states.
有两种不同状态
We have the normal state when we
正常状态下
show it on a map and it's a pin.
地图上有个大头针
And the user can tap on it or we
用户轻点大头针
can programmatically select it
程序就会自动选定它
and it becomes the selected
大头针图标变成了被选状态
state with a callout and show
上面就会出现标注
the title and subtitle.
并显示标题和副标题
There is a little drawback here
这有一个小小的缺点
and that is we only display the
就是大头针只有在选定状态下
title and subtitle if the pin is
才会显示
selected.
标题和副标题
So, as a user, you have to tap
所以
on everything to see what they
用户只能轻点所有图标
actually are, which is a little
才能知道这到底是干嘛的
bit cumbersome.
有点麻烦
So, as you saw in Maps app from
在 iOS 10 系统里
iOS 10, we use something that
我们用了
looks a little bit like this
类似这样的
instead.
图标
And with iOS 11, it's available
iOS 11 系统中
also to you.
这个也是可用的
We call it the
我们把它称为
MarkerAnnotationView.
MarkerAnnotationView（标记注解视图）
It is a AnnotationView subclass,
是注解视图的一种
so it's a sibling to the pin
和大头针注解试图
annotation view.
也有些类似
And we think you're going to
我们认为
like it so much that it's the
你们会很喜欢它
new default for iOS and tvOS.
这是 iOS 和 tvOS 的新默认状态
So, if you don't implement the
所以
delegate callbacks for creating
如果你没有选择
them yourself, we will give you
关掉它
a MarkerAnnotationView as
就会默认出现
default if you recompile against
标记注解视图
iOS 11.
如果你重新编译 iOS 11 系统
have two states.
会有两种状态
We have the normal state which
正常状态下
will try to display the title as
如果地图上有空余
well below the marker if there
标题出现在
is room on the map.
标记下方
We have the selected state.
还有被选状态
And in the selected state, we
被选状态下
also show the subtitle if there
若有空余
is room for it.
会显示副标题
And that way the user will at
这样的话
the glance at the map, see what
用户看一眼地图
are all of these data points
就可以知道
without having to tap on them
这些数据点是什么
one at a time.
而无需一一轻点
Now, there is one more thing.
还有件事
We have to go back to the pin
我们需要
one more time.
再看看大头针图标
If we look at this pin and the
来看一下大头针
callout, there is one small
及其标注
little thing in the callout.
标注也有一个小功能
You can add accessory views to
你可以
them.
在里面添加辅助视图
You can add detail views to
还可以
You can configure them.
添加细节视图
And MarkerAnnotationView is an
标记注解视图是
annotation view.
注解视图
So, all the API from annotation
所有注解视图的
views are supported for
应用程序接口
MarkerAnnotationViews as well.
也都支持标记注解视图
And if you add a in this case a
在这里如果
right accessory view to the
添加右辅助视图
callout, then there is no
在较大的标记里
natural location within the big
就无法
marker where you can display
自然地
that data.
显示这些数据
And it's even more obvious if we
显然
think about the detail view
我们想想细节视图
where you can put endless amount
你可以添加无限数量的数据
of data, a lot of data, a full
很多数据
placecard of your item if you
如果你想
want.
还可以放一整个座位卡的东西
So, what do we do in that case?
所以我们要做些什么呢
We have to use a third state of
我们需要标记注解视图
the MarkerAnnotationView.
的第三种状态
So, in practice, your
所以实际上
MarkerAnnotationViews have three
标记注解视图
states.
有三种状态
We have the normal state when
没被选择时
it's unselected.
是正常状态
We have the selected state.
被选状态
And the selected with callout
和有标注的
configure the marker annotation
若你设置了带视图的标记注解
with views that cannot be
但是标记显示不下
displayed in the marker alone.
就会启用该状态
And with that, let's look at the
让我们
code.
看看代码
This is the
这是
MarkerAnnotationView.
标记注解视图
The MarkerAnnotationView first
其最重要的是
and foremost you have the titles
它有题目
and you can configure the titles
而且你可以设置
that are displayed below it.
底下的题目
And notice that we yet again see
注意一下
this three-state enumeration,
我们又可以看到
the feature visibility.
三种视图状态的细目
Because you can configure it in
因为你可以
many different ways, not only
进行很多不同设置
visible and hidden.
不仅仅是可视和隐藏模式
The hidden obvious.
很显然
We don't show it.
隐藏模式就是不显示
The visible is also obvious.
可视模式也显而易见
We will always try to display
你设置可视模式后
the title and the subtitle if
我们会尽量
you configure them to be
显示
visible.
标题和副标题
Do note, I say we will try.
记一下 我说我们会尽力
If the map is dense with data,
若地图数据太密集
we will opt to hide the titles
我们就只能隐藏标题
to unclutter the map and display
使地图更加整洁
more information as needed.
显示更多必需信息
So, we will display them most of
所以 大部分时候标题是可视的
the time but they can be hidden.
但它们也可被隐藏
And in the last visibility we
最后一种可视性模式
have is the adaptive mode.
是适应模式
The adaptive mode is also the
这个模式
default mode which gives you
也是默认的
that for free option for the
你可自由选择副标题可视性
subtitle, especially where we
正常状态下
will hide it when it's in normal
是不显示的
state and display it when you're
被选状态下
in selected state.
是显示的
So, that is the title below the
所以这就是
marker.
标记下面的标题
Next up we have the markers
接下来
themselves that you can also
你还可以设置
configure.
标记
First with the color.
首先是颜色
So, there's the marker tint
这是标记着色
color and the glyph tint color.
这是图像符号着色
The marker color is the color of
标记颜色
the marker itself.
是标记自身的颜色
It is a normal UI color.
是正常的用户界面颜色
The default value is a nil value
默认值是零
which will pick a system
也是
default, which is currently a
系统默认颜色
slightly reddish color.
现在是红色
You can set it to any other
你也可设置成其他颜色
color you want, for example why
比如
not orange.
为什么不用橙色
Do note that we call it marker
注意我们把它叫做标记着色
tint color, not just color.
而不是简单的颜色二字
And that is because the color
是因为
you provide might not be the
你提供的颜色
color, the exact color that we
可能不是我们最后用的
use in the end.
那一个颜色
We may apply some visual effects
我们可能
on the color to make it look
会用一些视觉效果
nicer.
让颜色看起来更好看一些
So, it's a tint that you're
这是你可应用的
applying.
着色
And you can even use the new in
当然
iOS asset catalog name colors of
你也可用新 iOS 里面的
course.
颜色目录
And the same thing for the glyph
图像符号着色
tint color which is instead the
也是一样的
color of the glyph within the
是标记内
marker which is defaulting to
图像符号的颜色
white pin in this case.
默认是白色
Speaking of the glyph.
说到图像符号
You want to configure also what
你也会想设置
is inside of the marker, the
标记里面的东西
little glyph in it.
这个小图像符号
And the easiest way to do it is
最简单的办法是
by using the glyph text
设置
property.
图像符号文本性质
It's a simple string.
是很简单的字符串
We see a pattern here.
我们能看到一些规律
It defaults to nil.
默认是零
And when it defaults to nil, we
这时
pick a system default which is a
我们选择的系统默认
pin.
是大头针
It's a pin in a balloon.
在气球里的一个大头针
It might be dangerous, but it
可能会危险
works.
但是看起来很好
And you can set it to any text
你可以设置成
you want.
任何你想要的文本
You might want to grade your
你可以
annotations.
把注解分级
You can even use the characters
你甚至可以使用字符
or the Unicode standard to get
或统一字符编码标准
vector graphics for free.
自由设置矢量图
Now, glyph text is a string.
图像符号是一个字符串
So, you can set it to any text
所以
you want.
你可以设置成任意文本
If you want, you can put the old
如果你想
iliad into it and we will try to
你可以把伊利亚特放进去
render it.
我们会尽力显示
But it will look silly.
但看起来有点蠢
We will try to shrink down the
我们会尽力
text as much as possible but the
缩小文本
user will not really be able to
但
read what is on screen.
用户其实在屏幕上看不太到
So, as a rule of thumb, please
所以
try to limit yourself to around
尽量设置
two to three characters.
在两到三个字符内
And not everything though his
但
representable by characters or
不是所有的东西
text.
都用文本显示
Not even with the full Unicode
不仅是
standard being expanded every
统一字符编码标准
year.
每年都在扩大
So, you might want to use your
所以
own image graphics.
你可能想用自己的图形图像
And for that we have glyph image
所以我们有图像符号图形
and the selected glyph image
和
properties.
被选图像符号图形性能
The glyph image property is the
图像符号图形性能
only property that you probably
估计是
will want to use most of the
你最想用的
time.
且用得最多的性能
And you just give it an image
你可以提供
that is 40 x 40 points.
40 x 40 的图像
And when, which is used in the
这是
selected state.
在被选状态下的大小
And then for the normal state,
正常状态下
we will shrink it down to 20 x
我们会把它缩小到 20 x 20
Which works most of the time,
大部分时间这都是可行的
unless the graphics you have is
除非你的图像太细致
quite detailed, since then you
然后
can get graphical scaling
你就可以看到
artifacts as we scale it down.
我们缩小的器物
And if that is the case, you
如果这样
need to use both of the
你需要使用
properties.
这两个性能
So, for the small glyph image,
所以
you can provide the smaller 20 x
你可以提供 20 x 20 的小图
And for the larger one you give
和
it the bigger 40 x 40.
40 x 40 的大图
We will cross fade between the
然后
two and you get that crispiness,
我们会处理图像
both in the normal and selective
所以
states.
你可以在正常和选择状态下看到图像
And using that, we can get this
利用这项技术
much, much more modern-looking
我们就可
application.
让应用程序看起来更加 更加现代
Now, this application though is,
但现在
if I have to say so, a little
如果必须要说的话
bit cluttered.
这个应用程序有点混乱
You might want to clean it up
你可能会想整理一下
and have it easier to look at
使其看起来更简单
and find what you actually want.
找到你需要的内容
You want it to look a little bit
你会想让
more like this.
它这样显示
And there is one single property
在 iOS 11 系统里
that we add in iOS 11 to do
我们添加了一个性能
this.
可以做到这样
We call it the display priority
我们把它叫做显示优先级
where we can tell annotation
可以让注解视图
views what priority are you in
根据你的想法
order to display on the screen.
在屏幕上优先显示
The feature display priority is
显示优先级功能
modeled after the layout
是在 UIKit 和 MapKit 的
constraint priorities from UIKit
优先布局限制之后
and MapKit.
塑造出来的
Which means it's a floating
也就是说
point range between a 0 and 1000
它是在 0-1000 之间的
where 1000 is the required
浮动点区间
value.
1000 是必须的值
And if we look at what they do,
让我们看看它们能做什么
required means opt out.
必须值 意味着选择排除
Do not occlude or hide anything
在注解视图重叠时
as the annotation views overlap.
不挡住或隐藏任何东西
Do nothing.
什么都不做
But if you set the display
但若你把优先显示
priority property to anything
设置成了其他的
else, like the provider
比如
defaults.
defaults. 默认值
Default high which is 750 and
默认最高是 750
default low 250, yes, that's the
最低 250
layout constraints.
这就是布局限制
Then, you get these annotations
然后
hiding.
注解就会被隐藏
So, being a floating point value
浮动点值在 0-1000 之间
from 0 to 1000 means that you
意味着
can use it for nice things.
你可利用它 把地图变得更好看
If you for example map your
比如
display priority to the
如果根据受欢迎程度
popularity of your items.
来设置显示优先级
So, you have a high, a very
所以
popular item get the high
比较受欢迎的地点
display priority and a less
就会优先显示
popular item get a lower display
不受欢迎的地点的优先级就较低
priority, that would mean as the
也就是说
user is zoomed out on a high
用户把屏幕缩到很小
level and looking at the whole
俯瞰整个城市
city, the most popular items are
留在屏幕上
the one that is remaining on
能看到的
screen and visible.
是最受欢迎的地点
And as the user zooms in, you
用户放大后
see also all the other data.
可看到其他数据
Which allows you to go from this
这样
very cluttered map to something
混乱的地图
that is a lot cleaner.
就看起来整洁多了
Now, if you do the popularity
现在如果你是这么做的
then yes all the data is hidden.
数据就会被隐藏
So, the user will have to zoom
所以
in a bit to actually find it and
用户放大一点 才能发现次优先级的地点
then zoom out again to see the
缩小之后
rest of it.
可以看到其余的
And there is a better way to do
其实
it.
还有一个更好的方法
What we could do is just cluster
我们可以直接集中这些注解
the annotations and say that
是的
yes, here we have 11 more and
这里多了 11 个
here is 8 more.
这里多了 8 个
You don't have to zoom in.
无需放大
Well show you.
就会显示
And the API for this is just as
这个应用程序界面
simple as the API for display
和显示优先级的
priority.
一样简单
We call it a clustering
我们叫它聚类标识符
It is a string, so you can set
这也是字符串
it to anything you want.
所以你可以对其进行设置
It is modeled after the reuse
这是在重复使用标志符之后塑造的
Both annotations views, your
两种注解视图都可以
table view cells and collection
表格视图单元格
view cells.
和集合视图单元格
So, that you can have groups.
现有就有了群组
In the case of our application,
在我们的应用程序中
the bike sharing application, it
共享单车应用程序
might be that we want to cluster
我们可能会想
unicycles with unicycles and
把单轮脚踏车集中起来
tricycles with tricycles, but we
三轮车集中起来
don't want to mix them together.
但我们不想把两者混在一起
And if you can achieve that but
你若能达到此目标
give them those annotation views
给它们注解视图
different but distinct
以及不同于彼此的
clustering identifiers.
标识符
So, as you use it, the default
使用时
tis nil.
默认是零
If you set it to nil, you opt
若你设置为零
out and nothing happens.
选择排除后 什么都不会发生
And if you set it to any other
若设置成其他字符串
string, all annotations sharing
所有
the same annotation view are
相同的注解视图
illegible for being clustered
会重叠在一起
into a group as they overlap.
很难按类别区分
This is a very powerful and
这个功能很美很强大
beautiful feature but a little
但
bit hard to explain.
有点难解释
So, let me switch over to the
所以
demo machine and show it to you
让我来拿模型机
instead.
给大家展示一下
There is the demo machine.
这是模型机
So, in this little sample app, I
在这个简单的应用程序里
have four annotations.
我有四个注解
I have a unicycle and a second
这里有个单轮脚踏车
unicycle that share one
这还有一个
clustering identifier.
它们的聚类标识是一样的
And I have another tricycle and
这是三轮车
a tricycle sharing a second
这个也是
identifier.
它们的标识是一样的
If I move them together, we'll
如果移到一起
see their cluster.
就可以看到它们聚起来了
And if I drag them apart, they
把它们分开
decluster again.
它们也就散开了
Now, all four of these have the
这四个的
same display priority.
显示优先级是一样的
So, all four have the same
所以
display priority.
四个显示优先级别相同
When I group them together, the
我把它们
cluster will get the display
聚到一起
priority of the highest display
它们就会按照群组内最高优先级
priority within the group.
来显示
So, in practice, this means that
所以 实际上
in this example, both of them
这个例子里
still have the same display
这两个标识
priority.
有着同样的优先级
And when I move them even
如果
further together, they collide
我进一步缩小屏幕
and they hide each other.
它们就会碰到一起 合在一起
Move them out again and they
把它们分开
hide each other.
然后再把它们并起来
Now, if two annotation views
若两个注解视图
have the same display priority,
有着一样的优先等级
which one should we hide?
那么该隐藏哪个呢
And there is logic to it.
其实是有逻辑的
If we rotate the map a little
若我们把地图旋转一点点
bit and move them together, we
然后把它们合在一起
see we are still hiding the
还是绿色的
green one.
被隐藏了
If we rotate 180 degrees and
若我们旋转 180 度
move them together, we notice
然后把它们合在一起
the orange one is the one
现在
getting hidden.
橙色的被隐藏了
So, the logic here is if they
所以 逻辑就是
have the same display priority,
若优先级相同
we hide the one that is closest
我们把靠近屏幕顶端的注解
to the top of the screen.
隐藏起来
Which is good for developers and
这对开发人员和用户都有好处
users because you can see,
因为
expect what is going to happen
我们可以知道
next.
接下来会发生什么
But one of the many reasons this
但是其中一个原因是
was done, I have to say if we
我必须说
tilt the map into 3D mode, it
若我们把地图倾斜到 3D 模式
looks kind of cool as you rotate
旋转的时候
in the annotation behind the
一个把另一个挡住
other one.
看起来很酷
Now, let's zoom out a bit and
现在 让我把屏幕放大一点
drop another annotation on the
然后
map.
在地图上再放一个注解
Being in annotation view, you
注解视图中
inherit all the APIs from
有所有注解视图的
annotation view including
应用程序界面
dragging.
包括拖动
So, I can pick it up and drop it
所以 我可以把它拿起来
down again.
再放下去
I can pick it up, drag it around
拿起来 拖动它
and drop it down again.
然后再把它放下
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
Did you notice something
当我把它放到
happening there as I dropped it
海滩路上时
down close to beach street?
你们有没有注意到什么
So, look closely as I pick it up
看仔细一点 我把它拿起来
and drop it down on Dollar
然后把它放到租车行上面
It gets hidden.
它就被隐藏了
If you set the display priority
若你在注解视图里面
on annotation views, you will
设置显示优先级
also, we will also try to
我们也会
collide out items and labels on
把注解
the base map for you to keep the
和基本地图上的地点合起来
map even more uncluttered.
以使地图更加整洁
So, I can pick it up and why not
所以 我可以把它拿起来
drag it down, drop it down on
拖动它
another annotation and they
为什么不把它放到另一个注解上呢
merge in one smooth animation.
它们在平稳的动画之后会合在一起
All of these are actually
其实
draggable.
所有的都可以拖动
So, I can pick them up and pick
所以我可以把它们拿起来
them up, which is not true.
但这是不对的
Because the cluster itself is
因为
not draggable.
聚类是不能拖动的
In order to be a draggable
为了让注解能够拖动
annotation, you need to have a
你需要
coordinate.
一个坐标
And a cluster doesn't have a
聚类自身
coordinate on its own.
是没有坐标的
The geographical coordinate for
聚类的地理坐标
the cluster is the average of
实际上是
all the member annotations that
周围注解的
is currently encompassing.
平均值
And that is why you can't drag
这也是你为什么
it.
它无法拖动
But back to the slides.
回到幻灯片
It's a simple and powerful API
这是简单有力的一个应用程序界面
that allows you to go from this
可以让
cluttered mess to something a
混乱的屏幕
little bit more clutter
变得
cleanliness.
整洁一点
And this is good, since now we
这是很好的
see there are 11 annotations up
这有 11 个注解
there and we have two more up
那还有
there.
两个
And, but we don't really see
但是
what kind of annotations are
我们不能清楚地
there.
看到那是什么注解
So, being unicycles and
如果有单轮脚踏车
tricycles, I really don't want
和三轮车
to go to a location where there
我可不想过去了才发现
is only unicycles.
那只有单轮脚踏车
Because I haven't bothered to
因为
learn to ride one yet so I want
我不会骑
to make sure I go to a place
所以我要确保我去的地方
with tricycles only.
只有三轮车
So, we want to have the clusters
所以
display at the glance what kind
我们想看一眼这些聚类
of data do they contain at this
就知道这个地方
location.
有什么数据
And that we can do by doing our
我们可以
own custom annotation views.
通过定制注解视图完成
So, we can display it as a
也可以通过
little pie chart.
饼图来显示
And I can see, yeah, there are
我能看到
at least two tricycles there.
这里至少有两辆三轮车
It's safe, I can go there.
安心了 我可以去这里
How do we do this?
我们是怎么做到的呢
We have to go to our good old
我们借助了老朋友
friend the map view for
那就是
annotation delegate callback.
注解代表回调函数的地图视图
This delegate callbacks has
代表回调函数
always provided a system
一直都会为你
annotation for you.
提供系统注解
The user location annotation
用户定位注解
which is the representation of
代表的是
where is the user currently in
用户
the world.
现在在地球上所处的位置
And you can either return nil
你可以回到零点
value and you get the default
这样
pack.
就回到了默认包
Or you could return your own
或者你可
custom annotation and display
回到定制注解
the user location in a
以一种完全不同的方式
completely different way that
显示用户定位
fits your application needs.
来适应应用程序
And for everything else you DQ
适应其他
create your annotation view and
你定量设置的注解视图
return it.
然后返回
If you return nil, you get the
若你返回零点
system default which, in iOS 11,
就是系统默认
is the MarkerAnnotationView.
在 iOS 11 里就是标记注解视图
Now, in iOS 11, you will also
现在 在 iOS 11 里
get one more different kind of
你还有一个不同的注解
annotation, system annotation in
在你回调函数里的
your callbacks.
系统注解
You might get this
你可能会有
ClusterAnnotation.
聚类注解
So, if you opt into clustering
所以 若你选择聚类
and they collide, there is not a
然后它们碰到一起
new delegate callback.
是没有新回调函数的
We reuse the existing callback,
我们重新使用现有回调函数
give you a ClusterAnnotation
给你一个聚类注解
that represents the cluster, and
这代表了聚类
you can return the
而且你还可以
AnnotationView that you want.
回到你想要的注解视图
The ClusterAnnotation is a
聚类视图
simple concrete class of the
是注解协议的
annotation protocol.
一个简单的具体类
It provides you an array of all
给你提供了
the member annotations.
所有注解的一个数组
It's a flat array, so we
这是一个扁平化数组
guarantee that there will be no
所以我们可保证
clusters within clusters within
在聚类里面
clusters.
不会再有聚类
It's a flat array of all the
这只是
annotations that is currently
所有显示注解
representing and only those.
的扁平化数组
We order it so the one with the
我们给它排序
highest display priority is
第一个是
first.
最高的显示优先级
So, if you, as I said
所以 你若
previously, using display
像我之前所说的那样
priority and mapping it with
利用显示优先级
popularity, you will get the
并以受欢迎程度为根据
most popular one at the start.
那么最开始的就是最受欢迎的
The MarkerAnnotationView placed
标记注解视图和聚类注解
well with the ClusterAnnotation.
运行良好
So, we will display the count
所以我们可以把计数
there as the glyph.
显示为字符
So, you can see at a glance how
你看一眼
many there are.
就知道这里有多少
We will also, for the title and
我们也会为标题和副标题
subtitle, provide good default.
提供良好的默认模式
So, the title will be the title
题目就会是
of the most popular one or the
最受欢迎的地方
first member annotation.
或一等注解
And the subtitle is a localized
副标题是局部的加 X 数字
plus X number or more how many
或者是
annotations you want to have.
其他你想要的注解
Both of these properties are
这两个功能都是可变的
mutable, so you can change them
所以
anytime you want and provide
你可以随时变更
something else.
或提供其他选项
We might want to change it and
我们可能想改变它
have, say, three unicycles and
比如 三辆单轮脚踏车和两辆三轮车
two tricycles and then you can
所以
see at the subtitle what it is
即使没有定制注解视图
without doing a custom
你也可看到
AnnotationView.
注解字幕是什么
But you might want to do that
但是
custom AnnotationView.
你也可能想要定制注解视图
So, custom AnnotationViews.
所以定制注解视图
Let's look at this little pie
现在让我们看看这个小饼图
A AnnotationVview is a view.
注解视图是一个视图
A view has a frame.
视图就会有边框
And the underlying thing that
但
drives both display priority to
使显示优先等级
hiding things and clustering is
隐藏内容并聚集起来的潜在要求
that annotations must be able to
是注解必须能察觉到
detect if they are overlapping.
是否有重叠
And since we are views and we
既然是视图
have a frame, we can just use
还有边框
that frame and detect a
我们可以利用边框
collision.
来察觉碰撞
Now this doesn't look good.
这看起来不太好
I mean, they're circles, yes.
我是说 这是圆形的
The frames are colliding but
边框碰到了一起
visually they are not really
但是视觉上
colliding yet.
它们还没有碰上
So, this is not quite what we
所以
want.
这不是我们想要的
AnnotationView.
我们在注解视图里多加了一个性能
We call it collisionMode.
我们叫它碰撞模式
The default value is rectangle.
默认值是矩形
So, we have to use the frame.
我们必须利用这个边框
The other option we have is
我们的另一个选项是
circle.
圆形
Where we use the inscribed
这里的注解边框
circle of the frame for the
我们用的是
annotation.
內接圆形
And now when we move them
现在我们把它们放到一起
together, they collide and
它们会碰撞
detect a collision when they are
就会在视觉碰撞时
visually colliding.
察觉到碰撞
Now, not all AnnotationViews are
但不是所有注解视图
perfect boxes.
都是完美的形状
Some of them are actually
有一些还是
rectangles.
矩形
And for collisionMode rectangle,
碰撞模式的矩形
yes, the collision is with the
在碰撞时
rectangle.
用的还是这个矩形
But if you change it to the
但若把它改成圆形
circle, it is a circle.
它就变成了一个圆形
So, we use the inscribed circle
所以 我们就可以利用
in the rectangle, not the
矩形里的內接圆形
inscribed ellipses.
而不是內接椭圆
It's important to take a little
这里需要
bit of note there.
记一下笔记
So, not everything is rectangles
有的边框
or circles either.
不是矩形也不是圆形
We might have something a little
我们可能有
bit more fancy, like
好看一点的
nice-looking 3D rendered golf
比如 高尔夫应用程序上的
clubs for our golf application
好看的 3D 的
that is displayed in flyover.
高尔夫俱乐部的图标
And as we tilt the map in 3D and
我们把地图倾斜到 3D 模式时
we move them together, we want
把它们合到了一起
them to actually overlap a
其实是想稍稍重叠
little bit because it looks
因为
cool.
这样看起来很酷
It looks really nice, actually.
其实很好看
So, if we use just the
所以如果我们只用矩形
rectangles, they are way past
这早就
when we want them to detect
超过了
collision.
可察觉的碰撞范围
If we use the circles, no.
如果用圆形呢
it doesn't really fit either.
不行 这不太合适
I mean, what we really want is
我想说
something a little bit more
我们想要的是
close to this which would be the
类似这样的
circle in the bottom with the
就是底部的
five-point outset option that we
五点外嵌选项的圆形
did not give you [laughter].
我们之前没给过你们
You don't have that option,
对不起
sorry.
你们没有这个选项
Instead, we went back to all the
相反
way when outer layout was
我们回到了
introduced to both iOS and macOS
去年 iOS 和 macOS
in the year before.
引入外部布局的时候
And you have the alignment
你们有
rectangle insets which are the
直线矩形嵌入物
options that say that you can
若两个视图要排在一起
configure if two views re to be
你可以进行设置
aligned next to each other, what
那么
kind of insets would they use to
你要用什么样的嵌入物
look visually pleasing?
才能让它们看起来好看
Which is just what we're doing
这也是我们正在
here with the AnnotationViews,
对注解视图所做的事情
What is the visually pleasing
什么是
collision rectangle.
看起来好看的碰撞矩形
So, all you need to do.
所以 你要做的就是
Override it and you provide
覆盖它
offset.
但是找点什么补上去
So, for the top we can set it to
所以
50 points and we move the
上面我们可以设置 50 点
collision area down.
然后把碰撞区域移下来
The left edge, 0, we don't need
左边  0
to change it at all.
我们不需要改动
The bottom edge we move out by
底边 我们移动 -5
negative 5, because we want an
因为
outset, not an inset.
我们想要外嵌 不是内嵌
And then we do the right edge as
然后
well.
右边缘也这样改动
And what we have is that little
现在就是
circle in the bottom left outset
底部的一个五点外嵌小圆
by 5 points, just as we wanted.
是我们想要的
And when we now collide them, it
当我们把它们碰在一起的时候
looks very visually pleasing.
这看起来就很美观了
Let's look at the code to
让我们看看
configure our custom
设置
AnnotationViews.
定制注解视图的代码
And a few tips and tricks to
有一点建议和技巧
make our code base a little bit
可以代码看起来
more modern and nice.
更现代化 更美观
There we go.
开始吧
So, let's run the application
所以 先运行应用程序
first so we see that it works.
确保正常运转
Build succeeded.
建立成功
Compiling.
编译
It is running.
开始运行了
And we have the collision when
我们把它们放到一起时
we move them together.
它们发生了碰撞
They collide out.
它们分开了
So, it works.
所以 这是有效的
Now, looking at the code, we
看看代码
have our mapView, viewFor
我们有地图视图
annotation.
注解视图
The first thing we do is we
要做的第一件事是
check if that is one of our own
看看这是不是
annotations.
我们自己的注解之一
And if it is, we configure it a
如果是
lot to set it up.
我们把它进行大规模设置然后准备好
And otherwise we check if it's
否则
the system-provided
我们要检查它是不是系统提供的
ClusterAnnotation.
聚类注解
And if it is, we configure it
如果是
differently.
我们用不同的方法设置
And for the else case, we just
其他情况下
return nil to get the system
我们恢复零点
default.
回到系统默认
Currently that would be called
现在是
for all the user locations, but
所有用户的定位
it might be that we add more
但之后
system annotations in the
我们可能会
future.
添加更多的系统注解
So, good take.
所以 很好
Don't check for user location by
不要在默认时
default.
检查用户定位
Do the else case, return nil,
做其他的事 恢复零值
and let the system do the right
其他情况下
thing for all the other cases.
让系统来正确处理
Now, this is a lot of code, in
这有很多代码
our view controller nonetheless,
但是
and it doesn't really have
在我们的视图管理器看来
anything to do with how it's
这和其将如何显示
going to be displayed or rather
或者
it is all how it's going to be
所有的东西将如何显示
displayed.
没有任何关系
So, I don't think this should be
所以
in the view controller.
我觉得这不应该出现在视图管理器中
So, if I grab here and drag in a
所以如果
couple of views to my project, I
我把我的项目视图拖过来 加进去
think that first of all I know I
首先我要做的是
need to add these files to the
把文件加到目标文件里
target or it won't compile.
不然它不会编译
There we go.
就是这样
Another good tip is in your
注解视图的另一条建议是
AnnotationViews, you can
你可以不管
override the set annotation
设置注解方法
method and do the configuration
并
there.
进行配置
So, here I have the same thing.
同样
I know I will get a bike.
我知道会有一辆自行车
And if I get a bike, I configure
如果我得到了自行车
it, set it up, and be done with
我对其进行设置 准备 然后就完成了
it.
这可以让我
back here and delete all of
回到这里
this.
把这些都删掉
No, actually, not that one.
不对 这不行
And delete all of this, because
删掉所有的这些内容
it's really not fitting there in
因为这不适合
the view controller.
出现在视图管理器里
It gets a lot, lot smaller.
这小了很多
Another thing that might annoy
另一个可能会惹恼
SWF developers is that this view
SWF 开发人员的是
here is an optional.
这里的这个视图是可选的
We really don't want optionals.
我们不想要可选的
So, we want it to be normal
我们想要正常的
required variable.
需要变量的
Now, the DQ reusable annotation
现在 有视图的定量重复使用的
with view do return an optional.
注解的确恢复成可选的
But we fixed that and give you a
但是我们把它固定
sibling.
然后提供一个差不多的
The DQ reusable annotation with
有标识符的
identifier for annotation.
定量可重复使用注解
It is modeled after the DQ
这是根据
methods on UITableView and
用户界面表格视图和用户界面结合视图
UICollectionView.
的定量方法塑造的
So, it will always return an
所以
instance.
它总会恢复
Let's give it a, oops.
让我们来试试
Yeah. That's how you type.
这是你们打字的方式
And the annotation.
然后是注解
You might notice I did not have
你可能注意到了
US keyboard here.
我没有美语键盘
And by doing that, we no longer
这样的话
have to do the if check for did
我们就不需要检查
we actually do it and create it
我们到底做了没有
instead.
而是直接把它创造出来
We don't have to set the
我们无需设置注解
annotation, because we give it
因为
to the initializer.
我们把它
And we can just delete this.
交给了初始程序
Actually, let's go one further.
实际上 还可以进一步
We can delete all of this.
我们把这个都删了
We don't need that.
我们不需要这个
Because we can register our
因为
AnnotationViews to use for reuse
我们的注解
identifiers.
可以重复使用标识符
So, just as with the TableViews
在表格视图
and CollectionViews, we have
和集合视图中
tell the map view here, I want
我们倾斜了地图视图
to register.
我想注册
And use the bike view class for
利用自行车视图分类
any view with the reuse
以使用任何重复使用的标识符
identifier that could be of your
你就可以选取
choosing or one of the two
一个或两个
constants that we provide for
我们提供给你的
you.
常量
The default annotation view
我们在任何单独注解视图中
which we use for any single
使用的默认注解视图
annotation view created by the
是由
system and the default
系统创建的
ClusterAnnotation view that we
也是由我们在任何系统中的
use for any system annotation
默认聚类注解视图
view.
创立的
And now when we run it, it
现在我们运行的时候
compiles.
它就会编译
It runs. It launches.
运行 启动
And as we move them together
我们不用代码把它们移到一起
with no code, they merge.
它们就合起来了
And when we group them, we get
我们把它们组团时
the nice little pie chart.
饼图就更好看了
And that is a few tips and
以上就是
tricks for how to make
为你们提供的建议
AnnotationViews a lot easier.
以使注解视图更加简洁
Let's go back to the slides.
回到幻灯片
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
So, thank you for being here.
谢谢大家参加这次会议
Today we covered a lot of
今天
things.
我们讲了很多
First we have the new map type,
首先是新的地图类型
the muted standard, that allows
可淡去标准地图
your data to stand out on your
可以使你在应用程序中的数据
map in your application.
突出显示
We give you all of the map
我们提供了所有
controls as proper views so you
合适的地图视图
can configure in to display them
所以你可以设置显示
where and when it makes sense
随时随地显示
with the context of your
以
applications.
适应应用程序
We have the new
也有新的标记注解视图
MarkerAnnotationView that
可以
displays a lot more information
让你一眼
about your data at a glance
就看到更多信息
without having to dig in and out
而不用
of the data all the time.
一直都在寻找数据
And the MarkerAnnotationView
还有 标记注解视图
works beautiful with the new
与新的应用程序界面
APIs for display priority and
在显示优先级和聚类方面运行良好
clustering to get your data a
以使
lot more nicer looking and less
数据更美观
cluttered map.
地图更简洁
For more information, go to this
登陆这个网页
website.
可以查看更多信息
There is also the sample code
今天
for the application I've been
我也给大家展示了
showing you today.
应用程序的简单代码
Please play around with it and
请思考一下
see what great things can be
然后
done.
看看你能用它创造出什么
I'm very excited to see what you
我非常期待
will do with this.
看到你们将要进行的工作
Also, go back and watch the
对了
videos for What's New in
别忘了看看
Location Technologies from
昨天
yesterday.
定位技术最新分享的视频
And What's New in MapKit from
以及去年
2015.
MapKit 最新内容视频
Thank you very much.
非常感谢大家